at the University of Akran when when
Drew was in high school. So, um I've
been watching Drew since he was probably
14 or 15 years old. Um you know, offered
him uh as a college coach and um you
know, just amazing to see, you know, how
far he's come. Um not to say that I'm
surprised. um you know, you saw the
talent, you saw the ability, uh you
certainly saw the stature and you know,
all of those things, but um you know, to
see what he's accomplished and how far
he's come is is u you know, really u you
know, really cool for me, uh to see. And
now to have the chance to to have him
here in Pittsburgh and in in our
quarterback room, um I think is
outstanding. Um he is again, you know,
has rare size. He's, you know, 6'5, 235
lbs. He has big hands. Um, and I think
what's most exciting, you know,
certainly when you're talking about the
quarterback position is can this guy
throw the football? And I think he
throws it as well as any quarterback,
um, you know, in this in this draft
class. Um, he has an effortless arm. Um,
he can make every single throw on the
field. And, you know, he's a he's a
better athlete than I think given credit
for. you saw, you know, in in in a few
games, um, you know, this past year and
in the year previous, um, when the game
was on the line and he had to take off
and go, um, you know, he was able to do
that. Um, so I think that's, uh, that's
exciting. Um, but, you know, in addition
to, you know, the the the type of guy he
is and his intelligence as a football
player and, um, his arm talent and all
those things, um, I think he has a a
very high ceiling. Um, I don't think he
has reached his potential yet as a
player. Um and certainly um you know
coming here to Pittsburgh and and and
being um in a uh very quarterback uh
friendly system with coach McCarthy and
um you know his proven track record and
success of developing uh quarterbacks.
Um I really think this is a great spot
for Drew. It's great for the Pittsburgh
Steelers, but I think it's a great a
great place for Drew because I think
it's going to um I think our operation,
our organization, our coaching staff is
uh truly going to help him develop into
uh becoming the best player that he can
be.
>> Question.
>> What have you learned uh about Drew
personally just through the draft
process?
>> Well, um you know, I think I think a
lot. I think certainly um our our visit,
our 30 visit was uh was great for me.
Um, obviously, as I mentioned, you know,
kind of knew Drew as a as a young as a
young guy in high school. Um, but to
see, you know, him come in as, you know,
you know, a potential, you know, draft
prospect for us and to see his maturity
and his seriousness about the game, um,
and his intelligence, um, you know, I
think was really impressive. He is a
really sharp, uh, football player. He's
a sharp quarterback. Um, you know, he
will be, uh, he will be very enjoyable
for us to coach. Why hasn't he reached
his potential as you said yet? I'm not
just talking about potential where you
are coming out of college to be veteran
pros, but why hasn't it all coalesed for
him with all those tools that you
outlined? Well, you know, I think he's,
you know, he's still a young he's still
a young guy and I think that's part of
the process for every player as you as
you go through high school and
transition to college and, you know, you
go through, you know, your four or five
years at the college level and, you
know, there's another step to take, you
know, as you transition to becoming a
professional. And, um, you know, I think
that's, you know, it's not unique to
Drew. It's, you know, it's really what
you what you expect and I think what you
hope for. Um, you know, as a coach, I
don't know if, you know, you you're
looking at at trying to find a guy
that's a finished product. I think you
want to find someone who who has
potential to continue to improve and um,
you know, he certainly accomplished a
lot um, you know, in his college career.
Um, and you know, we think that, you
know, he has a he has a really high
ceiling.
>> As you watch the tape, what are some of
the specific areas he needs to improve
to reach that ceiling? Um, you know, I
think it's, uh, I think, you know,
really just, you know, just cleaning up
some of the fundamentals and the
footwork and being more consistent in in
those areas. Um, which, you know, was
one of the first things that Drew told
me, um, you know, when we had him here
on the visit, which, um, was really
refreshing, you know, to hear and, you
know, his his self-awareness, his
humility to, uh, you know, recognize,
hey, there's areas where I can be better
and, you know, where I can be more
consistent. And um you know when you
look at it and you and you look at it
from a quarterback coaching perspective
like the feet that's what you want to
that's what you want to coach up that's
what you you know you really feel
confident in um that you can u that you
can you know help improve it challenging
to get enough reps for Howard and Allard
as developmental quarterbacks.
>> Oh absolutely. I think um you know we'll
we'll have a great plan for that. Uh you
know fortunate have a have a really good
room you know right now. um you know
with Mason Rudolph and his experience um
you know certainly in the NFL but
obviously here in Pittsburgh um for both
uh Will and and now Drew um you know to
to to learn from
>> or should have
>> um you know I I don't I don't know you
know I don't believe that has any impact
on u you know on Aaron um you know
certainly you know we're we're we're
here for for Drew and excited about you
know his moment and and excited to have
him in this room.
>> One of the things that uh Omar talked
about throughout the process was that
you guys are looking for an AFC North
quarterback. Of those traits that he
has, what kind of tells you that he is a
guy that can play in the AFC North?
>> Well, yeah, I think there's a there's a
number of those traits. Um he's big, you
know, number one, he's a big strong uh
physical player. He has big hands. Um he
has a strong arm, you know, he's got a
you know, he's he's you know, built to
last. And um you know, I think that when
you're talking about playing in in the
elements and you know, playing the the
physical brand of football that that it
is in the AFC North, um you need a guy
like that. And um you know, Drew
certainly fits that mold.
>> With two young guys, you've got a
healthy competition now between Will and
Drew, no matter who else may or may not
be added to this room. What do you hope
that brings out from both of these young
guys?
>> Well, I think it'll bring out their
best. Um, you know, these are two ultra
competitive individuals. Um, you know,
they certainly wouldn't be where they
are in their careers if they weren't.
And um, you know, that type of uh that
type of competition uh typically brings
out the best in people and I know that
it will uh for for for both of them. Um,
you know, they know each other and you
know u uh Drew and I actually had that
conversation, you know, when he was on
his visit and say, "Hey, hey, how's that
how's that going to go?" coming into a
room with Will Howard and he's he was uh
he was excited. He said, "You know, I
got to know Will a little bit. He's a
great guy. He's a great player and um
you know, I'd love to I'd love to be
able to work with him." So, um you know,
I think that's I think that's exciting.
You know, when you have uh competition
and you have people that um you know,
really understand that at the end of the
day, like it's about it's about bringing
the best out in one another. And when
you have that healthy respect and that
healthy type of of competition, the
sky's is the limit. last one here.
>> This past year, Penn State obviously
didn't go the way he envisioned based on
your conversations with him and the work
you've seen him put in since. How do you
kind of gather that he handled that
adversity moving forward here even
though it kind of derailed his last year
at Penn State?
>> Yeah, that's a tough uh you know, it's a
tough uh situation to go through to you
know, dealing with injury. Um and you
know, certainly at you know, a very
critical time in his in his college
career. certainly, you know, for all of
his goals and dreams that he that he
wanted to accomplish at Penn State and,
you know, and certainly for, you know,
the ramifications that that, you know,
presents for, uh, you know, for his his
prospects, uh, you know, in the National
Football League. So, um, you know,
that's tough. and to see and to really
learn and hear about the type of
teammate that he was. Um, you know, the
way that he helped um, you know, his his
backup quarterback prepare, you know,
week in and week out and the meetings
that the two of them had, you know,
privately, um, you know, was really
impressive to me and I think it just
tells you the type of person that he is
and the type of teammate that he is. And
I think at the end of the day, like
he's, you know, he's obviously a very
good football player or we wouldn't, you
know, have have selected him. Um, but
he's a great person and he's gonna make
our team better. He's going to make our
locker room better.
>> All right.